(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-04T00:17:03.967162",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ゆらゆらり はらはらり
Swaying gently, softly wavering...
色とりどり 乱れ咲き
...vibrant colors blooming wildly.
花の街 思い出す
Reminding me of the flower town...
この空から
...from beneath this sky.
百花繚乱
Hyakka Ryoulan
ひょんな出来事から
From an unexpected turn of events,
やってきたこの場所は
the place where I have arrived...
遥か遠くにあった
...was once so far away...
煌びやかな舞台
...now a dazzling stage.
ハッとするほど鮮やかな世界が
I realized that a world so breathtakingly vibrant...
あるんだと知った
...truly does exist.
あなたの無理難題に答えていく
Answering every unreasonable challenge you throw,
その度に
each and every time...
あっと言わせるような奇想天外な
...with mind-boggling, jaw-dropping answers...
答え合わせで
...to see if we match,
辿り着いたその先に
and beyond where I have arrived,
新しい景色が待っているんだ
a brand new scenery is waiting.
摩訶不思議なミステリー
A wondrous mystery,
次から次に起こるたび
every time it happens one after another...
巧妙なからくりも 暴いてみせましょう
...I will lay bare even its most clever mechanisms.
どんな難題でも
No matter how difficult,
種や仕掛けはあるんだ
there is always a trick or secret.
副作用は気にしない
I won't worry about any side effects,
必ずや導き出すから
because I will always find the way.
あぁこの場所で触れた 人の哀しみや喜びがある
Ah, in this place, there are human sorrows and joys I've touched,
そのひとつひとつが 心を震わせる
each and every one of them makes my heart tremble.
ハッとしちゃうほど 鮮やかな世界がここにあるんだ
A world so vibrant it startles me is right here.
あなたの無理難題に 応えていく毎日に
To the everyday life of answering your unreasonable demands,
あっと言わせるような 奇想天外な答え合わせで
with a fantastic, mind-blowing matching of answers,
辿り着いたその先に 新しい私が待っているんだ
and beyond where we've arrived, a new me is waiting.
あの頃は 想像もしていない 未来が咲き始めている
A future that I couldn't have imagined back then is starting to bloom.
こんな日々も悪くはないかな
Days like this aren't so bad, I guess.
ゆらゆらり ひらひらり
Swaying gently, fluttering down...
離れては 寄り添って
drifting apart, then drawing close.
そよぐ風に身を任せ 幽夜に舞う
Entrusting myself to the gentle breeze, dancing in the dark night.
はーい！ということで！
Yees! And so!
今日、皆さん来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for coming today!
みんな見てる？見てますかー？
Is everyone watching? Are you watching?
ということで見て！今日はこの新衣装なんですよー！
And so, look! Today I'm wearing this new outfit!
みんな気づいたよね？気づいたよね、さすがに！
Everyone noticed, right? You must have noticed!
はーい！ということで見てください！この煌びやかな和風の新衣装です！
Yes! So please look at this glamorous, Japanese-style new outfit!
やったー！
Yay!
ということでですね、これは、今回『天女衣装』となっております！
So, this time, it's a "Celestial Maiden" outfit!
傘も合わせて見てください！傘！ちょっと見えるかな？
Please look at the matching umbrella too! The umbrella! Can you see it?
これ見て！
Look at this!
余のね、ちょっと衣装と同じ柄で、今回新しく作っていただきました！イェーイ！
This was newly made for me with the same pattern as my outfit! Yay!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
はい！ということで、この傘以外にもですね、ちょっとこの後、新しいアイテムもちょっと出てくるので、そちらも要チェックです！
Yes! So besides this umbrella, some new items will also appear later, so be sure to check those out too!
というわけで、1曲目は『百花繚乱』を歌って踊らせていただきました！
And so, for the first song, I sang and danced to "Hyakka Ryouran"!
あのね、ちょっと、花の蕾を使って、ちょっと新衣装にチェンジさせていただいたんですけど、どうでした？どうだった、どうだった？
You see, I used a flower bud to change into my new outfit, but how was it? How was it, how was it?
おほほほ、おお、ありがとうございます、ありがとうございます、可愛いですよね！
Oh ho ho, oh, thank you, thank you, it's cute, isn't it!
はい！ということで、今回のライブタイトルがですね、
Yes! And so, the title of this live stream is...
『天女繚華』ということで、ちょっとこの新衣装チェンジとか、これからのゲストの登場とかで
"Tennyo Enka". With this new outfit change and the upcoming guests' appearances...
ちょっとね、お花を多く使っているので
...we are using a lot of flowers...
『花が咲き乱れる』という意味を込めて、今回この『天女繚華』というライブ名にさせていただきました！
...so with the meaning of "flowers blooming in profusion," we named this live stream "Tennyo Enka"!
見て、ちょっと後ろにもちらっとお花が見えたり、余の衣装にもちょっとお花があったりなんたりしているんですけれども
Look, you can catch glimpses of flowers in the background, and my outfit also has some flowers here and there.
はい！ということで、この衣装に合わせて、今回も
Yes! So to match this outfit, once again...
ステージ新しく作っていただきました！やったー！
...they created a new stage for me! Yay!
え！めっちゃ綺麗じゃない？見て、この桜と、
Wow! Isn't it incredibly beautiful? Look at these cherry blossoms and...
このでっかい月！この、でっっかい月とね、この両端に、
...this huge moon! This huuuuge moon, and on both sides...
こっちにもありますけど、桜。いや、めちゃめちゃ綺麗でしょ！すごいでしょ、これ！
...there are cherry blossoms here too. I mean, it's absolutely gorgeous! Isn't this amazing?!
もうめちゃめちゃ考えました！もう、めちゃくちゃね、ちょっと運営さんたちと一緒に
I thought about it so much! I discussed it a whole, whole lot with the staff...
お話し合いをしたりとかして、こう、実現していただきました。本当にありがとうございます！
...and they made it happen. Thank you so much!
ということで、この横にもね、ちょっと、分かります？気づきました？
And also, on the sides, do you see? Did you notice?
ちょっとね、お花も、この、散りばめられていたり、余の足元にもね、この、
There are flowers scattered here and there, and even under my feet...
梅、なのかな？このお花を、こうね、ライトみたいな感じで照らしていただいてたり、
...are these plum blossoms? These flowers are illuminating the floor like lights...
こうちょっとね、細かくめっちゃ作ってもらってます！ありがとうございます！
...they've really paid attention to the finest details! Thank you so much!
なんで、それも含めて、ちょっとめちゃめちゃ見ていただきたいなと思っております！
So I really hope you pay close attention to all of that!
ま、このね、ま、ちょっと、ま、気になりますよね、この衣装。ちょっとみんなで近くで見てもらおうかな！じゃ、ちょっと上からいいですか？カメラさん。あ、ありがとうございます！
Well, I'm sure you're curious about this outfit. Shall we take a closer look together? Camera operator, can we get a shot from above? Ah, thank you!
あ、このね、気づきました？この、もう髪型からもちょっといつもと違うんですよ。ちょっとお団子。ま、
Ah, did you notice? Even my hairstyle is a bit different from usual. This bun...
いつものね、ちょっと3D衣装の雰囲気も残しつつ、残しつつね、ちょっと新しい髪型にさせていただきました！そして、そして、え、ちょっと、じゃ、ちょっといいですか？あ、あら！あら、可愛いですよね！
...while keeping the vibe of my usual 3D outfit, I got a new hairstyle! And, and, let's see, can we get a... Oh! Oh, it's so cute, isn't it!
あら、あら、あら、あら、あら...
Oh my, oh my, oh my...
このお花、そう、ステージのね
These flowers, yes,
足元にも入っているこの、梅っぽい花っぽい感じもいれていただきつつ
they've also included this plum-like flower design that's also on the stage floor.
この、見て！
Look at this!
見てください！
Please take a look!
この振袖にもちゃんとついてます、このお花！
These flowers are also patterned on my sleeves!
きれいでしょ？
Beautiful, right?
見て、きれいでしょ？
Look, isn't it beautiful?
よ、かわよでしょ？
Super cute, right?
いいでしょ？
Pretty nice, right?
はい、ということで、この足元にも
Yes! Also, I'd like you to
ちょっと注目していただきたいんですけど
pay some attention to my feet, but...
見て！この草履も新しくなりました！
Look! These sandals are also brand new!
かわいいよね、これ、左右でちょっと袖の色と合わせて
They're cute, right? The colors match my left and right sleeves.
こっちはね、白で
This one is white...
こっちは、ちょっと茶色っぽい感じになってます
and this one is a brownish color.
そして、この衣装すごいところがね
And the amazing thing about this outfit is,
どんだけ踊ってもですよ、足元見てください
no matter how much I dance... look at my feet!
めっちゃ伸びるんです、これ！
They stretch so much!
すごいでしょ、これ！
Isn't this amazing?
すごくない、これ？どんだけやっても
Isn't this incredible? No matter how much I stretch,
めっちゃ伸びるからね
they expand so much!
ということで、はい、紹介でした！
So, yes, that was my outfit showcase!
はい、じゃ、ちょっと、もうこの新しい衣装にもなりましたし
Okay, now that we have this new outfit
新しいステージにもなったということで、じゃ、ちょっと
and a brand-new stage,
ちょっと1枚、でもね、ちょっとお写真撮りますか、写真！
let's take a photo or two! A picture!
このせっかくだから、この桜のさ
Since we have these cherry blossoms
めっちゃ咲いてるところあるから、ここでちょっと撮ろうよ、撮ろうよ
blooming so beautifully, let's take a photo here!
じゃ、ちょっとカメラさん来てください、こっちこっちこっち！
Camera operator, please come over here. Over here!
あ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ映える、見て！
Oh! It looks so photogenic, look!
すごいでしょ、これ？めっちゃ綺麗だよね
Isn't this awesome? It's incredibly beautiful.
このね、桜の色とかもめっちゃ決めました
We put a lot of thought into the blossom colors.
めっちゃ、もうでもね、このライブ中にも
But you know, during the live concert,
めちゃめちゃ変わったりするので、ライティングとかもね
the stage lighting will change quite a lot,
変わったり雰囲気もまた変わるの
and the atmosphere will change completely.
それも含めて見てほしいんですけど
I want you to look forward to all of that, but...
まずちょっと、それを込めてちょっとここでお写真なんか撮っちゃおうかな
first, let's snap some photos here!
みんな、みんなスクショいっぱい撮ってくださいね
Everyone, make sure to take lots of screenshots!
みんなハッシュタグつけて、たくさんポストしてね
Tag them with the hashtag and post them!
撮ってる？撮れてる？
Are you taking them? Getting good ones?
いい感じ？いい感じか？
Looking good? Looking great?
じゃ、ちょっと、傘なしバージョンもちょっとやってみますか
Okay, shall we try a version without the umbrella?
どう？傘なし、傘なしもちょっと撮れるかしら
How is it? Let's take some photos without it too.
お、いいんじゃない？いいんじゃない？
Oh, looks good, right? Not bad!
あ、撮れてる？
Oh, are you getting them?
お、撮れてますか？
Oh, are we taking them?
おお、めちゃ、めちゃいい角度じゃん！
Oh, that's an incredibly good angle!
うわ、いいね、いいね、いいね！
Wow, nice, nice!
はい、じゃ、ということで、お写真はね、これくらいにさせていただきまして
Alright, we'll wrap up the photo time for now,
続きはね、ちょっと細かい衣装やら、ま、ちょっとスクショタイムはね
and as for the rest, like the fine details of the outfit,
人間ね、ちょっと要望かなと思うんで
I think you'll want more screenshot time,
まあその後もね、ミニライブとかもありますので
and we also have a mini-live coming up,
そちらもぜひぜひ、えー、チェックしていただければなと思います
so please check that out as well!
そして、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
And today's hashtag is this!
百鬼あやめ7周年新衣装3D
#NakiriAyame7thAnniversaryNewOutfit3D
で、ちょっとね、長いんですけど、長いんですけど
It's a bit long, but...
このたくさん綺麗な、このステージと
please take lots and lots of screenshots
よの綺麗な衣装を、たくさんたくさんスクショして、えー、一緒にポストしてください！
of this beautiful stage and outfit, and post them!
はい、ということで、今回は
Yes! So today's live concert...
えー、7周年を兼ねた、え、7周年！
is celebrating my 7th anniversary! 7 years!
ってことは、え、もう7年やってるんですか？っていう感じなんですけど
Wow, I've already been doing this for 7 years?
えー、今回はその7周年と、えー、新衣装お披露目を兼ねたライブとなっております
Today's live combines my anniversary and my new outfit reveal!
えー、これからね、ゲストもたくさん呼んでいますので
I've invited a lot of guests today,
楽しみにしててください
so please look forward to it!
なんと、なんと、最後には
And, incredibly, at the very end...
特大サプライズもあるので
there's also a huge surprise, so...
えー、絶対に最後まで見逃さないでね！
make sure you watch until the very end!
チャンネルはそのままだよ、頼むね！
Keep your channel tuned right here, please!
ひらひら ひらら
[Song: Hirahira Hirara]
夢の中でも
Even in my dreams,
花が散ってる
the flowers are scattering.
ひらひら舞う 暗闇に浮かぶ 桜
Fluttering, the cherry blossoms float in the darkness.
水面に落ちたら
If they fall upon the water's surface,
君は
will you...
もう一度咲くのかな
bloom once again?
桜月夜に宿る
Resting on a cherry blossom moonlit night,
いたずらな風
is a mischievous breeze,
匂いだけ残して
leaving behind only a scent,
騒ぎ出した
as it begins to stir...
It began to stir...
記憶は浮かび 沈んでいく
Memories float up and sink down...
思い出の破片が剥がれても
Even if fragments of memories peel away...
光る鱗で隠すの
I will hide them with shining scales...
まばゆいほどに美しい
They are dazzlingly beautiful...
ひらひら ひらら きらきら きらら
Fluttering down, glittering bright...
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Cherry blossoms floating in the darkness behind my eyelids...
水面に落ちたら
If they fall onto the water's surface...
君はもう一度咲くのかな
Will you bloom once more, I wonder?
サヨナラしたら 会えないのでしょう
If we say goodbye, we won't meet again, will we?
言えないままの気持ちだけが
Only these unspoken feelings...
花びら浮かんだ 桜の橋になれ
Float like petals, become a bridge of cherry blossoms...
当たり前の景色が
The everyday scenery...
ひらひらと舞い 音もなく消えてく
Flutters down and disappears without a sound...
細い雨に
In the gentle rain...
濡れた想いが 霞んでいく
My drenched feelings begin to haze over...
他の誰かに向けた笑顔見せ
Showing a smile meant for someone else...
忘れた日はよみがえる
The days I thought I'd forgotten are resurrected...
色のない夜を染めていく
Dyeing the colorless night...
君と出会った 去年の春と
In the spring of last year when I met you...
同じ場所で 同じ景色見つめてた
In the same place, we stared at the same view...
咲き誇るほどに 痛む
The more they bloom in full glory, the more it hurts...
君がいない桜
This cherry blossom season without you...
生まれ変わって また咲くのでしょうか
Even if reborn, will they bloom again, I wonder?
戻れない場所と知りながら
Knowing it's a place we can never return to...
散り行く花びら 手のひらにのせて
Placing the scattering petals on the palm of my hand...
花明かりに誘われて
Enticed by the cherry blossom's glow...
胸の中に降り積もる
It piles up deep inside my heart...
光と影 舞い散る吹雪の
Light and shadow, a dancing blizzard...
思い出だけ 白く染めていく
Only memories will be dyed in pure white...
ひらひら ひらら きらきら きらら
Fluttering down, glittering bright...
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ
Behind my eyelids, floating in the darkness...
桜 水面に落ちたら
Cherry blossoms, if they fall onto the water's surface...
君はもう一度咲くのかな
Will you bloom once more, I wonder?
サヨナラしたら 会えないのでしょう
If we say goodbye, we won't meet again, will we?
言えないままの気持ちだけが
Only these unspoken feelings...
花びらに変わっても
Even if they turn into petals...
君と出会った 去年の春と
In the spring of last year when I met you...
同じ場所で 同じ景色見つめてた
In the same place, we stared at the same view...
咲き誇るほどに 痛む
The more they bloom in full glory, the more it hurts...
君がいない桜
This cherry blossom season without you...
夢の中でも 花が散ってゆく
Even in my dreams, the blossoms scatter...
暗闇に浮かんだ 桜が
The cherry blossoms floating in the darkness...
水面に落ちたら また会えるのかな
If they fall onto the water, will we meet again?
極楽浄土
[Gokuraku Jodo]
月明かり昇る刻
Just as the moonlight rises with a glow,
灯る赤提灯
red lanterns start to light the scene.
祭囃子の合図
The music signals the start of the festival,
ふわり 蝶が 誘い出す
as fluttering butterflies gently entice you.
ちょいと覗いて見てごらん
Why don't you take a little peek inside?
迷い込めば 抜け出せない
If you wander in, you'll never escape.
楽しいことがしたいなら
If it's fun that you're looking for,
おいでませ 極楽浄土
welcome to Gokuraku Jodo.
歌えや歌え 心のままに
Sing and sing as your heart desires.
アナタの声を さぁ聞かせて
Come on, let me hear your voice.
踊れや踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance and dance, forgetting all about time.
今宵 共に ああ狂い咲き
Tonight, let's bloom wildly together.
美しく咲く花も
Even the most beautifully blooming flower
いつか散りゆくもの
will eventually wither away.
それならこの一夜を
If that's the case, then tonight,
もっと熱く愛したい
I want to love you even more passionately.
ちょいと「いいこと」いたしましょう
Let's do something "nice" together.
これは夢か幻か
Is this a dream or an illusion?
嘘も真も無い世界
In a world where there are no truths or lies,
ゆきましよう 極楽浄土
let's head to Gokuraku Jodo.
歌えや歌え 心のままに
Sing and sing as your heart desires,
乱れる髪、息も気にせず
with messy hair, not even caring if you're out of breath.
踊れや踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance and dance, forgetting all about time.
今宵 共に ああ狂い咲き
Tonight, let's bloom wildly together.
ちょいと「いいこと」いたしましょう
Let's do something "nice" together.
嘘も真も無い世界
In a world where there are no truths or lies,
ゆきましよう 極楽浄土
let's head to Gokuraku Jodo.
歌えや歌え 心のままに
Sing and sing as your heart desires.
アナタの声を さぁ聞かせて
Come on, let me hear your voice.
踊れや踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance and dance, forgetting all about time.
今宵 共に ああ狂い咲き
Tonight, let's bloom wildly together.
今宵 アナタと狂い咲き
Tonight, you and I will bloom wildly.
どいつもこいつも なんだかやっぱ脳天気
Everyone and their mother is so easygoing.
気になるあの子の悩みもきっとあるでしょ
But even that girl must have worries of her own, right?
そんで半端な憂鬱問答は群れを成し
Thus, half-baked melancholy questions gather in crowds,
あんたの頭の中はぐちゃぐちゃさ
making a complete mess inside your head.
ドンマイ 閉塞感が無いの？ 肯定式
Don't worry, is there no sense of closure? It's a positive mindset!
いけない いけない事柄なんて無いから
Because there is no such thing as an "unacceptable" matter!
イー・アール・サンスー じゃんけんぽんで さぁお湯
One, two, three, four, rock-paper-scissors! Now, the hot water...
ウーリュウチューパオクーでてんてこ舞いされてく
and oolong tea, completely spinning you out of control!
キミは もうハイスピードだ
You are already going at high speed!
ありゃま こりゃま お待ちかね
My, oh my, just what you've been waiting for!
ハチャメチャなドラマ
A chaotic drama!
派手にドラが乗るよ
The Dora tiles accumulate flashily!
いいいいなっきゅん I Love Youなのかな
A wonderful proposal... Is it "I love you"?
四六時中 愛を頂戴
Give me love 24/7!
はて？
Huh?
いいいいつばっきゅん I I I もラブ中
A wonderful kunoichi squeeze... I'm head over heels too!
1/2じゃ物足りない
Just a half of it is not enough!
それでも結局見えないアイツの胸の内
Yet in the end, I can't see that guy's heart
おしゃまな背伸びも気取りも要らないから
I don't need any pretentious posturing or showy behaviors
先輩 後輩 ヤンキー ジャンキー 関係ない
Seniors, juniors, delinquents, junkies, it doesn't matter
いざ尋常に勝負
Let's have a fair fight
君がもしもその気なら
If you're interested
boy meets girlが始まりそうならさ
If boy meets girl seems about to start,
まだ見ぬ技 繰り出す
I'll unleash an unseen skill
僕らってば so sweet だな アレなとこが同じだね
We're so sweet, you know, we're the same in that way
へちゃむくれな修羅場
In a messy scene,
派手に銅鑼が鳴るよ
the loud gong rings
意味深なlike you 曖昧な愛より直球
Deeply meaningful like you, I prefer direct pitches over ambiguous love
しのの言わず察してちょうだい
Please understand without me saying much
まて！
Wait!
いちびるな天罰！鼻血ブーなのだ
Don't be cheeky! I'm nose bleeding!
自分の意思はどんなもんじゃい
What about my own will?
い・い・許婚っきゅん i love youなのだ
I-I-my fiancée, I love you
四六時中 愛をちょうだい
Please give me love all the time
まって
Wait
い・い・一か八っきゅん i・哀・逢・愛 罠ろっきゅー
I-I-all or nothing! I-love-affection, trap rock!
1/2がもうたまんない
Half is just unbearable
これなんて試練
Is this some kind of trial?
運命かもしれん
Or maybe it's fate?
毎晩奇想天外
Every night, I'm in a fantasy,
足りないや
feeling inadequate
空前絶後 天真爛漫
Unprecedented, carefree
偏愛無常 免許皆伝
Impartial love, fully licensed
せーの
Ready, set...
いちにっさんはい！
One, two, three, go!
いよーーーーっ ぽん！
Iyo--- pon!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Haiya!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッ うー
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Woo...
さぁさぁさぁ
Come on, come on, come on!
これよりご覧いただきますのは
What you are about to witness
カブキ者たちの栄枯盛衰
is the rise and fall of kabuki performers.
時代は常に日進月歩 聞いてってよ老若男女
Time marches ever forward; listen closely, young and old!
一見は勧善懲悪 悪者どもを一刀両断
At first glance, it's good defeating evil, slicing the villains in two!
「でもホントにそれだけで楽しいの？」
"But is that really all it takes to be fun?"
もうなんだって蒟蒻問答
It's all just a nonsense debate anyway.
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Haiya!
ハッハッハッハッハッ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
いよーーーーっ ぽん！
Iyo--- pon!
どこからともなく現れて すぐにどこか行っちゃって神出鬼没
Appearing out of nowhere and vanishing just as fast, elusive as a ghost.
チャンスを待ったら一日千秋 追いかければ東奔西走
Waiting for a chance feels like an eternity; chasing after them keeps us running all over!
時代は常に千変万化 人の心は複雑怪奇
Times are always shifting; the human heart is a complex mystery.
「切でも本気でそんなこと言ってんの？」
"But are you really serious about that?"
もうどうにも満身創痍
We're already black and blue all over.
嗚呼、巡り巡って夜の町
Ah, wandering through the town at night...
キミは合図出し踊りだす
You give the signal and begin to dance...
はぁ〜
Haa~
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like petals scattering in a splendid flutter,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
with our hair flying wild!
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と
Two days ago, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after...
この宴は続く
this banquet will continue.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is the snow, moon, and flowers!
ほい！
Hei!
いよーーーーっ ぽん！
Iyo--- pon!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Haiya!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッ うー
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Woo...
ねぇねぇねぇ
Hey, hey, hey...
この世に平安訪れるの？のべつ幕なし丁々発止
Will peace ever come to this world? An endless clash of words...
兵ども千客万来 ひしめき合う群雄割拠
A flood of warriors crowding together, rivals contending for power...
一か八かの一攫千金 気が付いたら絶体絶命
All-or-nothing, chasing a sudden fortune, only to find ourselves in a desperate corner.
「でも本音のとこ、どうなってんの？」
"But what's the truth of it anyway?"
もうまったく奇想天外
It's just utterly bizarre.
嗚呼、たどりたどって夜の町
Ah, tracing our way through the town at night...
迷い一つなく踊りだす
We begin to dance without a single doubt...
はぁ〜
Haa~
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like petals scattering in a splendid flutter,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
with our hair flying wild!
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と
Two days ago, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after...
この宴は続く
this banquet will continue.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is the snow, moon, and flowers!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Haiya!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッ さぁさぁさぁ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Come on, come on, come on!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Haiya!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
花で一つ、
One for the flower,
鳥で二つ、
two for the bird,
手打ち鳴らす
clap your hands!
風で三つ、
Three for the wind,
鳴呼、月出て四つ
and four as the moon rises,
鳴らす鳴らす
making them ring, making them ring.
花で一つ、
One for the flower,
鳥で二つ、
two for the bird,
手打ち鳴らす
clap your hands!
風で三つ、
Three for the wind,
鳴呼、月出て四つ
and four as the moon rises,
鳴らす鳴らす
making them ring, making them ring.
今は
And now,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering flower petals in a gorgeous dance,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ
spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
shake your hair wildly!
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after...
この宴は続く
this feast will continue!
踊レ、歌エ、一進不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, and spin with absolute devotion!
今宵は何曜日か
What day of the week is it tonight?
水木金？
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday?
土日月火？
Saturday, Sunday, Monday, Tuesday?
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha haiya!
ハッハッハッハッ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
いよーーーっ　ぽん！
Yo... Pon!
宵々古今
[Song: Yoiyo Kokon]
らっしゃいな 平は成り 時が来た
Welcome! Peace is restored, the time has come.
正しい夢現 夜もすがら
A true state of half-dreaming all night long.
変わりゆくことに恐れなし
With no fear of changing things,
のっぴきならないのは御免
I refuse to get stuck in an unavoidable situation.
手毬唄歌い 君達が誘う
Singing a handball song, you all invite me in.
悪人に後ろ髪を惹かれても
Even if bad people pull me back with regret,,
進むべきなり
I must move forward.
流行り廃りの憂き世なら
If this is a fleeting world of trends and fads,
信ずる者はただ、君だけと
the only one I will believe in is you.
踊れ騒げや 呑めや歌えや
Dance and make a fuss! Drink and sing!
案ずることなどないな 此の世
There is nothing to worry about in this world.
人の世は恨めし 雪駄はちゃらちゃら
The human world is full of spite, my sandals clatter.
躱し躱され 狂って狂って 交じり騒いで
Dodging and being dodged, going mad and mingling in the uproar!
それそれそれそれ！
Sore! Sore! Sore! Sore!
今を嘆いて昔を化粧しても
Even if you lament the present and beautify the past,
君の心の内流るる涙川
a river of tears still flows inside your heart.
それじゃ敵わん 何処にいても
That won't do! No matter where you are,
めくるめく舞台に 君を連れて
I'll take you along to this dazzling stage!
あまりてなどか人の悲しき
Why is it that people have such excess of sadness?
身勝手なのが世の理か
Is selfishness simply the way of the world?
万人持つ理想 虚像の偶像
The ideals everyone holds are but hollow idols.
俗な答えなどはあらざらむ
There will be no vulgar, simple answers.
僕ら巡り逢うこと まさに一期一会
Our meeting is truly a once-in-a-lifetime encounter.
酸いも甘いも試練 連れ添ってこの手握って
Sharing the bitter and the sweet trials, let's hold hands and walk together.
生きづらい此処、浮き世から
From this fleeting world that is so hard to live in,
旗を掲げよ 宵闇が明く
raise the flag! The twilight is dawning.
酔いどれ上がれや 眠れば忘るる
Get drunk and cheer up! Once you sleep, you'll forget it all.
昔も今も変わらず 憂き世日 人の世は哀しい
Unchanged from past to present, life in this fleeting world is sorrowful.
いつだってちゃらちゃら 戯れて笑んで あい行きて
Always making noise, playing and smiling as we go along together.
それそれそれそれ！
Sore! Sore! Sore! Sore!
深まる春も 凍てつく雪の日も
In the deepening spring, and on freezing snowy days,
日出ずるすべての瞬きを君と見よう
let's watch every sunrise and twinkling moment together.
彩る色 どこまでも
Colors of every hue, stretching on forever,
空前なる見晴らしを 眺めて
as we gaze out at this unprecedented view!
負けて花一匁
Losing, we play Hana Ichi Monme...
欲しがる欲しがる欲しがる声
Voices calling, "We want them, we want them!"
勝って選んで 泣いて 去る真似の如何様で
Winning and choosing, weeping, playing tricks as if leaving...
満足に満ち足りないない
Never satisfied, never fully content!
未だ進む道半ばから
Since we are still only halfway on our path,,
如何なる時も歩を前へ出せ
no matter what, keep taking steps forward!
流行り廃りの憂き世なら
If this is a fleeting world of trends and fads,,
信ずる者はただ、君だけと
the only one I will believe in is you.
踊れ騒げや 呑めや歌えや
Dance and make a fuss! Drink and sing!
案ずることなどないな 此の世
There is nothing to worry about in this world.
人の世は恨めし 雪駄はちゃらちゃら
The human world is full of spite, my sandals clatter.
躱し躱され 狂って狂って 交じり騒いで
Dodging and being dodged, going mad and mingling in the uproar!
それそれそれそれ！
Sore! Sore! Sore! Sore!
今を嘆いて昔を化粧しても
Even if you lament the present and beautify the past,
君の心の内流るる涙川
a river of tears still flows inside your heart.
それじゃ敵わん 何処にいても
That won't do! No matter where you are,
めくるめく
Dazzling...
舞台に
To the stage...
宵々
Yoiyoi,
君を連れて
I'll take you along.
あまりてなどか 人ぞ悲しき
Why are people so sorrowful?
身勝手なのが 世の理か
Is selfishness the logic of this world?
うつろうは古今 炉頭なら堂々
Things transition past and present, like a censer in grandeur.
恐るることなどは あらざらむ
There is nothing to fear at all.
よぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉぉお！！！
Yoooooo!
じゅげむ じゅげむ ごこうのすりきれ
Jugemu, Jugemu, five-aeon rub-off...
かいじゃりすいぎょの すいぎょうまつ
Gravel-sand-water-fish, water-dwellings...
うんらいまつ ふうらいまつ
Cloud-dwellings, wind-dwellings...
くうねるところに すむところ
Where to eat, sleep, and live...
やぶらこうじの ぶらこうじ
Wild mandarin bushes, branches of mandarin bushes...
ぱいぽ ぱいぽ ぱいぽの
Paipo, Paipo, Paipo's...
しゅーりんがん
Shuuringan...
しゅーりんがんの ぐーりんだい
Shuuringan's Guurindai...
ぐーりんだいの ぽんぽこぴーの ぽんぽこなーの
Guurindai's Ponpokopii and Ponpokonaa...
ちょうきゅうめいの ちょうすけ保存
Long-lived Chousuke!
ちょいとお時間いただきます
Please lend us a bit of your time,
ご清聴ください 整いました！
please listen carefully. We are ready!
笑うこととかけまして
Take laughter, and what do you get?
お祭り野郎と解きます
An "omatsuri festival fellow"!
その心は？ その心は？
And why is that? Why is that?
どちらもハッピ（法被）になるでしょう
They both end up happy!
お後がよろしいようで
Thank you kindly for your attention!
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Laugh, laugh, come on, let's laugh!
こんな時代こそ 笑いましょう
In times like these, we must laugh!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
泣いたら負けだ やけくそ笑いましょう
If you cry, you lose! So just laugh desperately!
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも
Life has ups and downs, sour and sweet,
乗り越えた あっぱれ日本人
but the splendid Japanese overcome it all!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
どんな時でも なにくそ笑いましょう
Whatever happens, laugh with all your might!
ぐわっはっは
Gwah-hah-hah!
にょっほっほ
Nyoh-ho-ho!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Forget reading the room, just keep laughing!
笑顔！ 笑顔！ 笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smile! Smile! Smile! Smile!
笑う門には 福来たる！
Fortune comes to those who smile!
え〜 皆様 今日もようこそ おいでいただきました
Well, everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
ここで一席！
Now, let's begin!
ねずみの娘がお嫁に行って、じきに帰ってきたんで
A mouse's daughter got married and came right back,
ねずみのおかあさんが、大変怒って本地
so the mother mouse got very angry,
「あんな、いいところへ、おまえ嫁いで
"To such a wonderful place, you married in!"
誰が嫌で出てきたんだい？」"
"Who did you hate so much that you left?"
「いいえ、だーれも嫌じゃないんですけど、",s:
"No, I didn't hate anyone there,"
ご隠居さんがやさしいんで、嫌なの」"
"but the retired elder was so nice, I couldn't stand it."
「優しいんなら結構じゃないかねえ」",s:
"If he's nice, isn't that wonderful?"
「でも、猫なで声ですもの」"
"But he speaks in such a coaxing voice (purr).""
忙しさに身を任せて
Surrendering ourselves to the busy days,
消えていくだなんて べらんめえ！
to think we would fade away... Oh, please!
笑おう 笑おう 笑えなくても
Laugh, laugh, even if you can't laugh,
笑うしかないでしょ 笑いましょう
there's no choice but to laugh, so let's laugh!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
口角上げて ひたすら笑いましょう
Raise the corners of your mouth and just keep laughing!
鬼の乱、大飢饉さえ
Even the rebellion of demons and great famines,
クリアして現代日本人
we cleared them all to become modern Japanese!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
未来へいざなう グハハと笑いましょう
Leading us to the future, let's laugh out loud!
小娘のたわごとと切り捨てないで
Don't just brush it off as a young girl's nonsense,
しかめっ面なんか変な顔
a scowl is such a strange face.
笑顔を見たいから
Because I want to see your smile...
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Laugh, laugh, come on, let's laugh!
こんな時代こそ 笑いましょう
In times like these, we must laugh!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
泣いたら負けだ やけくそ笑いましょう
If you cry, you lose! So just laugh desperately!
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも
Life has ups and downs, sour and sweet,
乗り越えた あっぱれ日本人
but the splendid Japanese overcome it all!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
どんな時でも なにくそ笑いましょう
Whatever happens, laugh with all your might!
ひたすら笑いましょう
Just keep laughing!
ぐわっはっは
Gwah-hah-hah!
にょっほっほ
Nyoh-ho-ho!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Forget reading the room, just keep laughing!
笑顔！ 笑顔！ 笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smile! Smile! Smile! Smile!
笑う門には福来たる！
Fortune comes to those who laugh!
「死んでも夢を叶えたい」
"I want to make my dream come true even if I die."
「いいえ、死んでも夢は叶えられる」
"No, dreams can be achieved even after death."
「それは絶望？それとも希望？」
"Is that despair? Or hope?"
「過酷な運命乗り越えて」
"Overcoming a harsh fate,"
「脈がなくても突き進む」
"We charge forward even without a pulse."
「それが私たちのサガだから！」
"Because that is our saga!"
誰が弔う 死地は彼方
Who will mourn? The place of death is far away.
静寂を破り 芽吹いた夢を 誓え
Break the silence, swear on the sprouting dream.
穿て
Pierce through!
重なる 屍高みへ
Upon the piling corpses, rise higher!
届くまで
Until we reach it!
唸れ
Roar!
徒花 朽ち果てても進め
Though we bear no fruit, we charge on even if we rot!
奪わせはしない 尊厳の愚弄に
We won't let them steal from us, as they mock our dignity,
飢餓を解き放て
unleash your hunger!
枯れても走ることを命と呼べ
Even if we wither, call our running "life"!
空に叫ぶ 脱・生存の定義
Shout to the sky, the definition of post-survival!
骨を斬らせて 闇を断て
Let them cut our bones, and we shall sever the darkness!
雲間に光る 簒奪の勝機
Shining through the clouds, the chance for usurpation!
覚悟を宿命に突きつけて
Thrust your resolve in the face of fate!
天下に狂い咲く
Blooming in madness across the land,
サガ SAGA
our saga, SAGA!
傷ひとつ無い 手など愚か
Hands without a single scratch are foolish.
意思も自由も その身を投げて
Throwing away both will and freedom,
守れ
protect them!
退くな
Do not retreat!
涙も血も無い 神話を
A myth with neither tears nor blood...
築くまで
until we build it!
燃えろ 修羅花
Burn up, flowers of carnage!
鼓動亡き世界で
In a world without a heartbeat,
摂理に抗い 天命も無礼に
we resist providence, defying even heavenly decree,
腐鎖切り抜けて
breaking through our rotting chains!
心を無くすことが死と知れ
Know that losing your heart is true death!
極めど儚い 偶像の寵児
The ultimate, yet fleeting, darling of idols,
目には目を剥き 牙を剥け
glare eye for eye and bare your fangs!
いつか誰もが散華する捨て石
Someday we will all fall like discarded pawns,
輝け 刹那無限の火花
so shine bright, infinite sparks of a fleeting moment!
乱世に迸る
Gushing forth in this troubled world,
サガ SAGA
our saga, SAGA!
何が神の冒涜か
What is desecration of God?
裁きなどさせない
We won't let them judge us!
希望 高らかに打ち鳴らせ
Ring out hope loud and clear!
呼吸よりも生きた証
A proof of being alive, more than mere breathing!
唸れ
Roar!
徒花 朽ち果てても進め
Though we bear no fruit, we charge on even if we rot!
奪わせはしない 尊厳の愚弄に
We won't let them steal from us, as they mock our dignity,
飢餓を解き放て
unleash your hunger!
枯れても走ることを命と呼べ
Even if we wither, call our running "life"!
空に叫ぶ 脱・生存の定義
Shout to the sky, the definition of post-survival!
骨を斬らせて 闇を断て
Let them cut our bones, and we shall sever the darkness!
雲間に光る 簒奪の勝機
Shining through the clouds, the chance for usurpation!
覚悟を宿命に突きつけて
Thrust your resolve in the face of fate!
荒野を駆ける 乱世に挑む
Running through the wasteland, challenging the troubled times!
天下に狂い咲く
Blooming in madness across the land,
サガ SAGA
our saga, SAGA!
渡月橋 〜君 想ふ〜
Togetsukyou ~Thinking of You~
寄り添う二人に 君がオーバーラップ
Seeing two people together, your image overlaps them
色なき風に 思い馳せて
I send my thoughts on the colorless wind
触れた手の温もり 今も...
The warmth of your hand when we touched... even now
Stop 時間を止めて
Stop, please make time stand still
そう いつの日だって
Yes, no matter what day it is
君の言葉 忘れないの
I'll never forget your words
会いたい時に 会えない
When I want to see you, I can't
切なくて もどかしい
It's so painful and frustrating
から紅に 染まる渡月橋
Togetsu Bridge is dyed in deep crimson
導かれる日 願って
Wishing for the day I'll be guided to you
川の流れに 祈りを込めて
I put my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you
いつも こころ 君のそば
My heart is always by your side
いにしえの景色 変わりなく
The ancient scenery remains unchanged
今 この瞳に 映し出す
Now reflected in these eyes of mine
彩りゆく季節 越えて
Passing through the colorful changing seasons
ねぇ 覚えていますか？
Hey, do you still remember?
ねぇ いつになったら
Hey, when will the time come
また 巡り会えるのかな
when we can meet each other once again?
会いたい時に 会えない
When I want to see you, I can't
この胸を 焦がすの
This feeling burns deep within my chest
から紅に 水くくるとき
When the river is tie-dyed in deep crimson
君との想い つなげて
Connecting my feelings to yours
川の流れに 祈りを込めて
I put my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you
いつも 君を探してる
I'm always searching for you
君となら 不安さえ
If I am with you, even my anxiety
どんな時も 消えていくよ
will fade away, no matter the time
いつになったら 優しく
When will the time come when you will gently
抱きしめられるのかな
hold me in your arms?
から紅の 紅葉達さえ
Even the deep crimson autumn leaves
熱い思いを 告げては
whisper their passionate thoughts...
ゆらり揺れて 歌っています保存
...as they gently sway and sing
I've been thinking about you
いつも いつも 君想ふ
Always, always thinking of you
はい！というわけで、ここまでどうでしたでしょうか？
All right! So, how did you like it so far?
いや、もう数多くのゲストに出ていただいて、
We had so many guests join us today,
もう余は本当に嬉しいです！本当に。
and I'm incredibly happy! Truly.
今回のライブは最初にも言ったんですけど、ちょっと和風な感じでまとめさせていただいたので、
As I mentioned at the beginning, I styled this live show with a traditional Japanese theme,
もう曲も、もうほぼほぼ全部和風っぽい感じで、ちょっと雰囲気をね、ひとつに統一して、今回はライブを作らせていただきました！
so almost all the songs have a traditional vibe to unify the atmosphere for this show!
そして！みんな気付いたかな？ちょっと歌ってる最中、ちょっと、気付きました？これ。
And! Did everyone notice? While I was singing... did you notice this?
おっ、気付きました〜？
Oh, did you notice?
新しいマイクなんですよ！すごいでしょ！そうそうそう。
It's a brand new microphone! Isn't it awesome? Yes, exactly!
えっ、見て見て！このちょっと、この、分かりますか？このお腹の柄と...
Look, look! Do you see this pattern... on the belly here, and...
ちょっとお揃いなんですよ
They actually match, you see!
ちょっとこっちも、顔、あ、見えるかな？見える？
Let's see if we can see the face on this side too... Can you see it?
ほら、え、めっちゃ可愛いでしょう、これ！
Look! Wow, isn't this super cute?!
イェーイ、これ新しいマイク。あ、ここもね、飾りも付いているんですよ、この鈴と、
Yay! This is my new mic. Oh, it also has decorations here, like this bell...
この紐もね、付いていて。可愛いでしょ？
...and this cord. Cute, right?
はーい。これもおニューです。やったー！
Yes, this is brand new too! Yay!
はい。ということで、今回はですね、まだサプライズが残っております！
All right! So, actually, we still have another surprise left today!
ですが！
However...
えー、その前にちょっと告知をさせていただこうかなと思います！
...before that, I have some announcements to share with you all!
それでは、告知、ドン！
So, here is the announcement!
百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズ！イェーイ！
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Celebration Merch! Yay!
はい。ということで、最初は、こちら！
First up, we have this!
えー、卓上屏風です！めっちゃ可愛いでしょう、すごい！
The desktop folding screen! It's so cute, amazing, right?!
でしょう？えーと、デスク、デスクに立てて飾れるサイズの屏風となっております。
Right? It's a screen sized perfectly to stand up and decorate your desk.
こちらはですね、我美蘭先生の描き下ろしの、本日着ている新衣装と同じです！
This features an illustration by Gabiran-sensei, showing the same new outfit I'm wearing today!
同じ屏風をね、ちょっと飾ってくださいね、みんな。はい。え、可愛いでしょ？
You can decorate your space with the same screen. Isn't it cute?
このね、ステージも、背景のステージも、ちょっとそれっぽい感じに合わしていただきました。可愛い！
Even the background stage here was designed to match that style. So cute!
続いて、こちら！
Next up, this!
湯呑みとなっております！えー、こちらはですね、三川あゆむ先生に描き下ろしいただいた、
The tea cup! This features an illustration by Mikawa Ayumu-sensei...
えー、ぽよよに乗っかっている、今回も、こちらの新衣装で、えー、乗っているのがミニキャラで描かれた湯呑みとなっております。
It's a chibi illustration of me riding Poyoyo in this new outfit!
可愛いでしょ？こうやって、こうやって乗ってます。乗ってます。
Isn't it cute? I'm riding on it just like this.
はい。可愛いでしょ？そして、続いての、こちら！
Yes, super cute! And next, we have this!
こちら、扇子となっております！
This is the folding fan!
こちらはですね、あ、気付きますか？こちらもそうです、新衣装と同じ柄の、えー、扇子となっております。
You might notice that this fan has the exact same pattern as my new outfit.
ちょっとね、ど真ん中に「余」って入っているんですけど、こちら、えー、入れるかすごい迷いました。これ「余」を入れる、入れようかな、え、どうしようかな、とみなさんとちょっと話し合って、
It has 'Yo' written right in the middle. I actually hesitated a lot about whether to include it or not, and discussed it with the staff.
こちらになりました！
But we ended up going with this design!
ちょっとね、あの、この「余」の右、左で、こう「余」のこれかな？この振袖と同じこっちの色と、こっちの色で、ちょっとね、新衣装っぽい感じにさせていただきました。
To the left and right of 'Yo', the colors match my long sleeves, giving it a very 'new outfit' vibe.
としてそして！続いて、こちら！
And next up, we have this!
卓上ライトとなっております！
The desktop light!
行灯風の卓上ライトで、新衣装にこちらもですね、合わせた、えー、和風のデザインとなっております。
It's an andon-lantern-style desktop light with a Japanese design matching my new outfit.
ぜひね、飾って、あの和風っぽい風情ある、えー、お部屋タイムをね、過ごしていただきたいなということで、ちょっと和風寄りのライトにさせていただきました。
I wanted you to have a relaxing, atmospheric time in your room with a traditional Japanese touch, which is why I chose this style.
可愛いでしょ、これ。いいよね？
Isn't it cute? I think it's great!
めっちゃ考えました、こちら。おすすめです。はい！
I put a lot of thought into this one. Highly recommended!
はい、続いて、こちら！
All right, next up, we have this!
こちらですね、お馴染み、えー、販売ボイス、こちらのタイトルは「新衣装でデート」ということで、内容は新衣装の「余」と水辺で、
As always, we have the voice pack! This one is titled 'A Date in My New Outfit.' The story is about going on a date with me...
え？水辺？
Wait, by the water?
デートしている内容となっております。ま、ステージにもね、ちょっと水辺、あ、後ろにありますけども、はい。
Yes, a date by the water! In fact, there's water on this stage behind me too.
はい、そしてそして、えー、フルセットをご購入の方は、こちらです！
And for those who purchase the full set, you get this!
えー、数量限定バージョンは直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り、えー、我美蘭先生描きおろしのポストカードとなっております！
The limited-quantity version includes a postcard drawn by Gabiran-sensei with a hand-signed autograph and foil-stamped message!
可愛い！
So cute!
え、通常バージョンはですね、箔押し複製サインと、えー、メッセージ入りの、えー、我美蘭先生描きおろしポストカードとなっております。
The standard version features a postcard drawn by Gabiran-sensei with a foil-stamped replica signature and message.
さらに、新衣装をリスナーに褒めてもらって喜んでいる「余」の特典ボイスがついてきます！ね。はい。
It also includes a bonus voice track of me getting happy after being praised for my new outfit by my listeners!
タイトル「またデートしようね」という、これは一体何なんだという感じなんですけど、
The title is 'Let's go on another date.' What's that all about, right?
まあね、あの、気になる方はぜひ、あの、聞いていただければと思います。まあ、恥ずかしいのでここら辺にしておきます。
Well, if you're curious, please give it a listen. It's a bit embarrassing, so I'll stop talking about it here!
はい。ということで以上、えー、百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズでした！みなさん、買ってね！よろしくお願いします！
So, that's all for Nakiri Ayame's 7th Anniversary Celebration Merch! Everyone, please check them out! Thank you!
と、いうことなんですけど、
And that's that, but...
こちら、まだ終わってません！
We are not done yet!
まだチャンネルはそのままで頼む！
Please stay tuned to the channel!
ということで、まあね、最初ちょっと言った、そろそろ、まあ、サプライズをね、
As I mentioned at the very beginning, it's finally time for...
みなさん、気になってると思うんで、ちょっとサプライズにいっちゃおうかなと思います。みなさん、気になるよね？
...the surprise! I'm sure you're all curious, so let's get right to it. You want to know, right?
気になる、気になるー！
We do, we do!
え、そうですよね！
Of course you do!
と、その前に、このステージ、上へ参ります！
But before that, this stage is going up!
うわ！上あがってる！え、みんな見て、すごいでしょ？
Whoa! It's going up! Everyone, look at this, isn't it amazing?
え、見てる？見えてる？
Can you see it? Are you watching?
みんな見て！ステージも、「余」も見て！
Everyone, look! Look at the stage, and look at me!
はい、ということで、
All right, so...
こちら上に上がってきたんですけれども
I've come up here to the stage...
ま、上でね何をするのかと
And what will I be doing here?
ま、うすうすちょっと気づいてるんじゃないかなとは
You might have some inkling already...
ま、思うんですけれども
I think, but...
何か分かるかな？
Do you know what it is?
みんな、教えて、教えて、教えて、みんな何だと思う？
Everyone, tell me! What do you think it is?
何だと思う？
What do you think?
お、なんか、お、ちらほら
Oh, I see some...
お、当たってますね。うん、うん。なんと！
Oh, you got it right! Yes! It is indeed...
はい、こちら、なんとこちらです！ドドン！
Yes, this! It's this! *Drumroll*
新曲「花吹雪」です！やったー！
A new song, "Hanafubuki"! Yay!
いや、もうだいぶ長らくお待たせしたと思うんですけれども
I know I've kept you waiting for a very long time,
お嬢のオリジナル曲の「新しいのはいつだ？」みたいなので待っていたかと思うんですけど
you were probably wondering when my next original song would be.
えー、こちら、えー作詞・作曲、Vell さんに書いていただきました。
Well, this song was written and composed by Vell-san.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much!
テーマはですね、「可憐な歌声 × 和風ロック」
The theme is "lovely vocals x Japanese-style rock."
可愛いだけじゃない、一味違うオリジナルソングと
It's a different kind of original song that isn't just cute.
なっております。
from my usual.
はい、このね、こう綺麗な可憐で、こう重厚な和風ロックとなっておりますので
Yes, it has a beautiful, lovely, yet heavy Japanese rock style.
メロディとかね、歌詞もこだわり抜いて、え、磨き上げていただいた楽曲となっておりますので
We put a lot of care into polishing both the melody and lyrics.
ぜひぜひ皆さん、え、聞いてください。
So please, everyone, have a listen!
え、9月4日0時から、本日の0時からですね
It's releasing today, September 4th at midnight—
え、各種音楽サイトでリリースされるのでぜひ聞いてください。
on various streaming platforms, so check it out!
聞いてね、いっぱい聞いてね。
Listen to it a lot, okay?
はい。
Yes!
それでは皆さん、大変長らくお待たせいたしました。
And now, thank you so much for waiting.
え、最後はこの新曲「花吹雪」で、え、お送りさせていただきたいと思います。
To finish off, I'd like to perform "Hanafubuki" for you.
え、感想などもね、え、この衣装も、ステージと一緒に、え、ポストしてください。
Please post your thoughts on the outfit, stage, and song!
たくさん、ポストしてね。
Post lots of them, okay?
え、最後にはですね、メンバー限定パートで、え、ちょっと衣装のお写真あったり、詳しい感じのお話もしたり
In the members-only stream after this, we'll look at outfit details and chat more...
え、ミニライブもありますので、そちらの方もぜひぜひ見に来てくれたら嬉しいです。
and there's a mini-live too, so I'd love it if you could join!
はい。
All right.
それでは、
Then,
お聞きください。
please listen to...
「花吹雪」
"Hanafubuki."
共に散る宿命なら
If our fate is to scatter together,
派手に散りましょう
then let us fall grandly —
花吹雪
a storm of blossoms.
ひらひら舞い落ちる空
Fluttering, falling through the sky—
とうに散った泡沫の夢
dreams like bubbles that burst long ago.
千の花は麗しく咲く
A thousand flowers bloom in breathtaking beauty;
叶う逢瀬は刹那
the encounters we wished for last but a moment.
艶やかに舞う
Gracefully dancing —
蝶の儚き命
a butterfly’s fleeting life.
するり堕ちる今宵は何処
Where will its wings carry it tonight?
天の風揺れて
The heavenly wind trembles.
狂おしく今咲き誇れ
Now, madly, bloom with pride!
共に散る宿命なら
If our fate is to scatter together,
光満ちた舞台で舞え
then let us dance upon a stage of brilliant light.
闇を裂く旋律は
The melody that tears through the darkness
ゆらりと薫る
sways and gently perfumes the night.
夢を咲かせましょう
Let our dreams bloom
花吹雪
in a storm of blossoms.
くらくら燃ゆるは焔
Dizzying flames burn brightly;
遠く咲いた明くる日の夢
dreams of tomorrow blooming in the distance.
正か否か惑わずにいこう
Right or wrong, let us go without hesitation,
過去の痛みを胸に
carrying the pain of the past in our hearts.
誰そ彼に
In the twilight,
祈りをひとつ
a single prayer,
涙の川を
a voice that pierces
穿つ声響く
the river of tears.
慎ましくただ進むだけ
Modestly, simply, just keep moving forward.
茜さす空の果てで
At the end of the crimson-glowing sky,
褪せた過去の憧れを見る
I see the faded longings of the past.
澄み渡る静寂に
In the clear, vast silence,
未来を繋ぐ
connecting to the future.
答え求むれど
Seeking an answer...
にべも無し
...but none is given.
星の降る夜明けまで
Until the dawn when stars fall,
続く歌よ彼方へ届け
o endless song, reach across the distance.
湧き上がる情熱が世界を照らす
This passion rising within will set the world alight.
共に散る宿命なら
If we are destined to fall together...
光満ちた舞台で舞い上がれ
...soar high on this stage filled with light!
闇を裂く旋律は
The melody that tears through the darkness...
ゆらりと薫る
...gently wafts.
夢を咲かせましょう
Let's make our dreams bloom...
花吹雪
...into a flurry of falling cherry blossoms!
7周年!!ライブ見てくれてありがとう!!
Thank you so much for watching the 7th anniversary live!
新衣装にキレイなステージどうだったかしら!?
How did you like the new outfit and beautiful stage?
みんなが少しでも笑顔になってくれたら嬉しいですッッ
I'd be so happy if I made you smile, even just a little!
8年目もよろしくね～っ!!!!! なきり♡
Please support me in my 8th year too! - Nakiri <3